Edward L. Bernays Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Client, Institution, and Organization File, 1916-1964 (Box I:56-421)
  - Horse Show of Art, 1932-1933 (Box I:191)
  - Hospital for Joint Diseases, New York, N.Y., 1958-1961
  - Hotel Association of New York, 1922-1923 (Box I:192)
  - Howe & Lescaze
    - 1931-1932
    - 1932 (Box I:193)
      - Jan.-June
      - May-Dec. (Box I:194)
    - 1933
  - Hutton, Barbara See Container I:350, Troubetzkoy, Barbara Hutton
  - Independent Oil Companies of America, 1933
  - India Information Service (Box I:195)
    - 1949-1952
    - 1951-1952 (Box I:196)
    - 1951-1952 (Box I:197)
    - 1952 (Box I:198)
      - Feb.-Apr.
      - Apr.-Aug. (Box I:199)
  - Indian Refining Co., 1924 (Box I:200)
  - Individual Drinking Cup Co., 1932-1933
  - Institute of Effective Speaking and Personality, undated
  - Institute of Inter-American Relations, 1926
  - International Artificial Flower Trade Service, 1929
  - International Arts and Crafts Exposition, 1923
  - International Film Congress, 1926 (Box I:201)
  - International Library Bureau, 1933-1934
  - International Pediatrics Association, 1947
  - International Psycho-Analytical Press, 1920-1922
  - Isbrandtsen Steamship Lines, 1947
  - Jewish Mental Health Society, 1928 (Box I:202)
  - Joint Council of New York State Psychologists on Legislation, New York, N.Y., 1954-1956
  - Junior Monthly Book Service, 1926-1927
  - Kahn, Ely Jacques, 1930-1931 (Box I:203)
  - Kapp & Hoffenstein, 1925
  - Kastor, Robert N., 1922
  - King, Wilfred, 1933
  - Klaw, Joseph and Alonzo, 1920
  - Klaw, Marc (Box I:204)
    - French Leave, 1920
    - General
      - 1920-1921, (9 folders)
      - 1921-1922, (2 folders) (Box I:205)
    - J'Accuse, 1921
    - Sonya, 1921
    - We Girls, 1921 (Box I:206)
    - Yellow Jacket, 1921
  - Knickerbocker Village Committee, New York, N.Y., 1933-1934 (Box I:207)
  - Knox Gelatin Co. (Box I:208)
    - 1924-1928
    - 1927-1928 (Box I:209)
    - 1927 (Box I:210)
      - Apr.-Dec.
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:211)
    - 1928-1929
    - 1928, Feb.-Oct. (Box I:212)
    - 1928-1929 (Box I:213)
    - 1929-1930 (Box I:214)
  - Kossuth, Egor, 1921
  - Ladies' Home Journal (Box I:215)
    - 1931
    - 1931-1932 (Box I:216)
    - 1932 (Box I:217)
    - 1932 (Box I:218)
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Feb.-Nov. (Box I:219)
  - Le Boutillier, 1921-1922 (Box I:220)
  - League of New York Theaters, 1949
  - Lehigh Portland Cement Co., 1925
  - Leinsdorf, Erich, 1944, 1952-1953
  - Lelong, Lucien, 1931
  - Lewis, Mary, 1938 (Box I:221)
  - Life Extension Institute, 1921
  - Liggett & Myers Tobacco Co., 1927-1928
  - Lighthouse for the Blind, 1919-1921
  - Light's Golden Jubilee (Box I:222)
    - 1929
    - 1929 (Box I:223)
    - 1929 (Box I:224)
    - 1929 (Box I:225)
      - June-Aug.
      - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:226)
  - Lipton, Estelle L., 1922-1923 (Box I:227)
  - Lithuanian National Council, 1919-1921
  - Loft, Inc., 1935-1937
  - Lowell, Joan, 1929
  - Lowry, Helen Bullitt, 1922
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1945-1946
  - Lucy Stone League, 1922-1923
  - Luggage Information Service, 1927
  - McAlpin Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1922 (Box I:228)
  - McCalls
    - 1946-1949
    - 1949 (Box I:229)
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Mar.-May (Box I:230)
      - Apr.-May (Box I:231)
      - May-Aug. (Box I:232)
      - June-Aug. (Box I:233)
  - Macfadden Publications
    - 1926-1927
    - 1927-1928 (Box I:234)
  - McKey, Joseph V., 1933 (Box I:235)
  - McKinley, Barry, undated
  - Mack Trucks, Inc.
    - 1948-1950
    - 1950 (Box I:236)
    - 1950-1951 (Box I:237)
    - 1950-1951 (Box I:238)
    - 1950 (Box I:239)
      - June-Aug.
      - Aug.-Oct. (Box I:240)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:241)
    - 1951
      - Jan.
      - Jan.-Apr. (Box I:242)
      - May-Sept. (Box I:243)
      - Sept.-Nov. (Box I:244)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:245)
    - 1952
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Feb.-June (Box I:246)
      - June-Dec. (Box I:247)
  - Macy & Co., 1922 (Box I:248)
  - Madison Square Garden Corp., 1935
  - Magazine of Wall Street, 1929-1930, 1936-1937
  - Malcoskey, Edna Walker, 1931-1932
  - Market Research Corp. of America, 1938
  - Mary Imogene Basset Hospital, Cooperstown, N.Y., 1929
  - Mayer & Associates, 1947
  - Mayflower Associates, 1933-1936 (Box I:249)
  - Medalie, George Z., 1931-1932
  - Medical Administration Services, 1941 (Box I:250)
  - Mendelsohn, Sigmund, 1926
  - Merchants' Association of New York, 1937
  - Merritt-Chapman & Scott (Box I:251)
    - 1932-1949
    - 1955-1958 (Box I:252)
    - 1957-1959 (Box I:253)
    - 1957-1959 (Box I:254)
    - 1959 (Box I:255)
    - 1959 (Box I:256)
    - 1959-1960 (Box I:257)
    - 1959-1961 (Box I:258)
    - 1960 (Box I:259)
    - 1960 (Box I:260)
    - 1961 (Box I:261)
  - Meter Service Corp., 1929 (Box I:262)
  - Metropolitan Educational Television Association, 1958
  - Metropolitan Music Bureau, 1919 (Box I:263)
  - Metropolitan Opera Co., 1916
  - Middle of the Road Recovery Committee, 1934
  - Miller, Gilbert, 1922
  - Motor Fair Price League, 1921
  - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Co.
    - 1943
    - 1943 (Box I:264)
  - Nash-Kelvinator Corp.
    - 1936-1937
    - 1936-1938 (Box I:265)
    - 1936-1938 (Box I:266)
    - 1936 (Box I:267)
      - May-Aug.
      - Aug.-Oct. (Box I:268)
      - Oct.-Nov. (Box I:269)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:270)
    - 1937
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Mar.-July (Box I:271)
      - Aug.-Dec. (Box I:272)
    - 1938 (Box I:273)
    - 1938 (Box I:274)
  - National Association for Mental Health, 1948-1949
  - National Association of Broadcasters, 1950-1951
  - National Association of Chain Drug Stores, 1943 (Box I:275)
  - National Association of Glue Manufacturers
    - 1945-1947
    - 1951 (Box I:276)
  - National Association of Secondary School Principals, 1950
  - National Better Business Bureau, 1950
  - National Board of Fire Underwriters
    - 1941
    - 1941 (Box I:277)
  - National Committee for an Adequate Overseas Information Program (Box I:278)
    - 1954-1955
    - 1954-1958 (Box I:279)
    - 1955 (Box I:280)
    - 1955 (Box I:281)
    - 1955-1956 (Box I:282)
    - 1955-1958 (Box I:283)
    - 1956-1960 (Box I:284)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1948 (Box I:285)
  - National Cystic Fibrosis Association, 1960-1961
  - National Household Service, 1928
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1938
  - National Macaroni Manufacturers Association, 1949
  - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1954-1961
  - National Pharmacy Committee (Box I:286)
    - 1943
    - 1943 (Box I:287)
    - 1944 (Box I:288)
  - National Probation and Parole Association, 1956-1960
  - National Prosperity Bureau, 1922
  - National Recreation Association, 1960-1961
  - National Starch Products, 1954 (Box I:289)
  - National Statistical Survey of Business Attitudes, 1934-1935
  - National Sugar Refining Co., 1933-1934 (Box I:290)
  - National Surety Co., 1933-1934
  - Negbaur & Co.
    - 1960
    - 1960-1961 (Box I:291)
  - New Jersey Telephone Co., 1925
  - New Orleans Item, 1954-1955
  - New Republic, 1946
  - New York City Anniversary Committee, 1952-1953 (Box I:292)
  - New York County Lawyers' Association
    - 1961
    - 1961 (Box I:293)
  - New York Infirmary for Women and Children, 1933
  - New York Merchants' Association, 1939
  - New York Real Estate Securities Exchange (Box I:294)
    - 1929
    - 1929 (Box I:295)
      - July-Aug.
      - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:296)
    - 1929-1930 (Box I:297)
  - New York Real Estate Securities Exchange (Box I:298)
    - 1930
  - New York State Bar Association, undated (Box I:299)
  - New York State Optometric Association
    - 1939-1944
    - 1944 (Box I:300)
  - New York State Psychologists Association, 1955
  - New York State Reconstruction Commission, 1920
  - Non-Partisan Fact Finding Committee for Herbert Hoover, 1932
  - Norway, undated (Box I:301)
  - O'Dwyer, William
    - 1940
    - 1940 (Box I:302)
  - Orvis, Ina Leland, 1930
  - Park & Tilford, 1933 (Box I:303)
  - Patenotre, Jacqueline T., 1957
  - Patterson Brothers Tobacco Co., 1923
  - Pauley, Edwin W., 1935
  - Peabody, Ernest H., 1928
  - Pearl Associates, 1938-1939
  - Pennsylvania, Ohio, & Colorado Miners' Relief Committee, 1928 (Box I:304)
  - Pennsylvania Optometric Association, 1942-1945
  - Philco Radio and Television Corp.
    - 1934-1937
    - 1934-1935 (Box I:305)
    - 1934-1937 (Box I:306)
    - 1934-1937 (Box I:307)
    - 1935-1936 (Box I:308)
  - Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York, N.Y., undated (Box I:309)
  - Philipp, John, 1921-1922
  - Play-of-the-Month Guild, 1950-1951
  - Play Schools' Association, 1955
  - Posner Shoes, 1930
  - Postgraduate Medicine, 1948-1949
  - Printers' Ink, 1953-1957 (Box I:310)
  - Procter & Gamble Co. (Box I:311)
    - A-B
    - B-C (Box I:312)
    - C (Box I:313-314)
    - D-H (Box I:315)
    - H-M (Box I:316)
    - M (Box I:317)
    - M-P (Box I:318)
    - P (Box I:319-320)
    - Q-R (Box I:321)
    - R-S (Box I:322)
    - S (Box I:323-328)
    - S-W (Box I:329)
  - Propeller Club, 1951 (Box I:330)
  - Public Education and Child Labor Association, 1946
  - Public Education Association, 1938
  - Pullman Co., 1939
  - Queensboro Corp., 1923
  - Rabinowitz, Aaron, 1929
  - Racine, Wis., 1934
  - Rezoning Protest Committee, 1939-1940 (Box I:331)
  - Roheim, Geza, 1928
  - Russian Exposition, New York, N.Y., 1929 (Box I:332)
  - St. Dennis Offices Corp., 1921, 1927-1928
  - St. George Hotel, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1937 (Box I:333)
  - Schenley Industries, 1935-1936
  - Schicht Co., 1924-1927 (Box I:334)
  - Schulte Stores (Box I:335)
    - 1932
  - Schulte-United
    - 1928-1929
    - 1928-1929 (Box I:336)
  - Seligmann & Co.
    - 1926-1927
    - 1927-1928 (Box I:337)
  - Senior Citizens' Committee
    - 1956
    - 1956 (Box I:338)
  - Sherry-Netherlands Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1949-1950
  - Shubert, Milton I., 1930-1931 (Box I:339)
  - Smith, Carl A., 1946
  - Social Science Research Council (Box I:340)
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935 (Box I:341)
  - Spalding & Brothers, 1937-1938 (Box I:342)
  - Spanish Child Welfare Association, 1938
  - Starrett Brothers, 1935-1936
  - State Bank of Long Beach, 1957 (Box I:343)
  - Stearns Co., 1929
  - Steinway & Sons, 1951
  - Stevenson, W. Yorke, 1920
  - Stewart & Co., 1929
  - Stix, Baer & Fuller Co., 1944-1946
  - Straus Co., 1921-22
  - Street and Smith Publications, 1950
  - Sunroc Refrigerator Co., 1950
  - Tanners' Council of America (Box I:344)
    - 1945-1947
    - 1945-1947 (Box I:345)
    - 1946 (Box I:346)
    - 1946-1947 (Box I:347)
  - Telephone Message Bureau, 1928 (Box I:348)
  - Terhune, Albert Payson, 1932-1933
  - Third War Loan Campaign Committee, 1943 (Box I:349)
  - Tobe & Associates, 1947-1950
  - Trainer, Wortham & Co.
    - 1957
    - 1957 (Box I:350)
  - Travelers Aid Society, 1938-1942
  - Troubetzkoy, Barbara Hutton, 1949
  - Trunk Luggage and Leather Goods Manufacturers, 1925-1927
  - Uniformed Firemen's Association of Greater New York, 1950-1951
  - United Brewers' Industrial Foundation (Box I:351)
    - 1936-1937
    - 1936-1937 (Box I:352)
    - 1937 (Box I:353)
    - 1937 (Box I:354)
      - Mar.-June
      - June-Aug. (Box I:355)
    - 1938 (Box I:356)
  - United Fruit Co. (Box I:357)
    - 1942-1945
    - 1942-1945 (Box I:358)
    - 1943-1946 (Box I:359)
    - 1943 (Box I:360)
      - Mar.-May
      - June-Oct. (Box I:361)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:362)
    - 1944
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.-June (Box I:363)
      - July-Dec. (Box I:364)
    - 1945 (Box I:365)
      - Jan.-July
      - Aug.-Dec. (Box I:366)
    - 1946-1947 (Box I:367)
    - 1946, Apr.-Nov. (Box I:368)
    - 1946-1947 (Box I:369)
    - 1947 (Box I:370)
    - 1947-1948 (Box I:371)
    - 1948-1950 (Box I:372)
    - 1949 (Box I:373)
      - Mar.-Dec.
    - 1950
      - Jan.
      - Feb.-Dec. (Box I:374)
    - 1951-1959 (Box I:375)
    - 1951-1959 (Box I:376)
    - 1951 (Box I:377)
      - Jan.-July
      - July-Dec. (Box I:378)
    - 1952
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-Dec. (Box I:379)
    - 1953 (Box I:380)
      - Jan.-Aug.
      - Sept.-Dec. (Box I:381)
    - 1954 (Box I:382)
      - Jan.-June
      - June-Oct. (Box I:383)
    - 1954-1955 (Box I:384)
    - 1954 (Box I:385)
      - Nov.-Dec.
    - 1955
      - Jan.-Apr.
      - May-Oct. (Box I:386)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box I:387)
    - 1956
      - Jan.-Aug.
    - 1956-1957 (Box I:388)
    - 1956 (Box I:389)
      - Sept.-Dec.
    - 1957
      - Jan.-Dec.
    - 1958 (Box I:390)
    - 1958-1959 (Box I:391)
    - Undated (Box I:392)
  - United Parcel Service (Box I:393)
    - 1958-1961
    - 1960-1963 (Box I:394)
  - United States Government (Box I:395)
    - President's Committee on Government Contracts, 1950-1954
    - President's Emergency Committee on Employment (Box I:396)
      - 1930-1931
      - 1930-1932 (Box I:397)
    - War Department, 1919, 1925
  - United States Sugar Beet Association (Box I:398)
    - 1942
    - 1942-1943 (Box I:399)
  - Uris Brothers, 1952 (Box I:400)
  - Vacuum Oil Co.
    - 1926-1930
    - 1930-1931 (Box I:401)
    - 1930-1931 (Box I:402)
    - 1931 (Box I:403-404)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States, 1949-1953 (Box I:405)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States, Ladies Auxiliary
    - 1938, 1946
    - 1946-1947 (Box I:406)
  - Victory Book Campaign, 1942
  - Vienna, Austria, 1927
  - Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1937 (Box I:407)
  - Wallace, Henry Agard, 1932
  - Walska, Ganna, 1928
  - Ward Baking Co.
    - 1924
    - 1924 (Box I:408-410)
    - 1924-1926 (Box I:411)
    - 1928-1929 (Box I:412)
  - Wasey & Co., 1941
  - Watson, Archibald, 1930-1931
  - Waumbec Mills, 1955-1956 (Box I:413)
  - Wemyss, George J., 1928
  - Western & Southern Life Insurance Co., 1951 (Box I:414)
  - White, Harry C., 1927
  - Whitman & Goodman, 1929-1930
  - Whitney National Bank, 1961 (Box I:415)
  - Wiener, Felix F., 1920-1921
  - Wildenstein & Co.
    - 1945-1947
    - 1947 (Box I:416)
    - 1947-1948, 1954-1958 (Box I:417)
  - Winston, Inc., 1934-1935 (Box I:418)
  - Wise, Ethel H., 1943
  - Wolfson Family Foundation
    - 1959-1960
    - 1960-1961 (Box I:419)
  - Worker-management survey, 1941 (Box I:420)
  - Woods School, Langhorne, Pa.
    - 1934-1939
    - 1934-1948 (Box I:421)
  - Worth, Inc., 1926-1928
- Part I: Speech and Article File, 1919-1967 (Box I:422-449)
  Drafts, printed copies, press releases, notes, research material, correspondence, and inquiries.
  Arranged chronologically. A partial index is filed in Container I:422.
  - 1919-1934 (Box I:422)
  - 1934-1935 (Box I:423)
  - 1936 (Box I:424)
  - 1936-1937 (Box I:425)
  - 1937-1938 (Box I:426)
  - 1938-1940 (Box I:427)
  - 1940 (Box I:428)
  - 1940-1942 (Box I:429)
  - 1942-1944 (Box I:430)
  - 1944 (Box I:431)
    - March
    - Apr.-June (Box I:432)
    - June-Dec. (Box I:433)
  - 1945 (Box I:434)
  - 1945-1946 (Box I:435)
  - 1946-1947 (Box I:436)
  - 1947 (Box I:437)
  - 1948-1949 (Box I:438)
  - 1948-1950 (Box I:439)
  - 1951-1952 (Box I:440)
  - 1952-1953 (Box I:441)
  - 1953-1954 (Box I:442)
  - 1954-1956 (Box I:443)
  - 1956 (Box I:444)
  - 1956-1958 (Box I:445)
  - 1958 (Box I:446)
  - 1958-1961 (Box I:447)
  - 1961-1967 (Box I:448)
  - Undated (Box I:449)
- Part I: Book File, 1890-1965 (Box I:450-466)
  Drafts, galley proofs, notes, research material, correspondence, and inquiries.
  Books are arranged in chronological order of publication. Research notes for Biography of an Idea are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Crystallizing Public Opinion (1923) (Box I:450)
  - Propaganda (1928)
  - Speak Up for Democracy (1940)
  - Take Your Place at the Peace Table (1945)
  - Public Relations (1952) (Box I:451)
  - Engineering of Consent (1955)
  - Crystallizing Public Opinion (1961 edition) (Box I:452)
  - Biography of an Idea: Memoirs of Public Relations Counsel Edward L. Bernays (1965) (Box I:453)
    - Final draft with corrections
      - pp. 1-806
      - pp. 807-1746 (Box I:454)
    - Preliminary drafts (Box I:455)
    - Sections
      - Nos. I-V
      - Nos. VI-VIII (Box I:456)
    - Research notes (Box I:457)
      - Alphabetical file
        - Adler, Cyrus
        - Aeolian Co.
        - Akins, Zoe
        - Allerton House Corp.
        - Allied Chemical & Dye Corp.
        - American Safety Razor Corp.
        - American Tobacco Co.
        - Ansco Photo Products
        - Appleby, Paul
        - Art Lamp Manufacturing Co.
        - Backer, George
        - Bank of America
        - Bara, Theda
        - Barnum, P. T.
        - Beck, Thomas
        - Bern, Paul
        - Blumenthal, Sidney
        - Bok, Edward W.
        - Bolton, Francis Payne Bingham
        - Boni & Liveright
        - Bookman, Judith
        - Boomer, Lucius
        - Bourjois, Inc.
        - Bridges, Harry
        - Broun, Heywood Campbell
        - Brown Durell Co.
        - Burchell, Frederick D.
        - Byoir, Carl
        - Cartier, Pierre
        - Cheney Brothers
        - Clark, Frederick G.
        - Coburn, Charles
        - Coolidge, Calvin
        - Cooper, Mrs. Kent
        - Copeland, Royal S.
        - Corcoran, Thomas G.
        - Cornwall, Anne
        - Curtis Publishing Co.
        - Dewey, Thomas E. (Box I:458)
        - Dodge Brothers
        - Donovan, William J.
        - Dort Motor Co.
        - Duncan, Isadora
        - Edison, Thomas A.
        - Elliott, James W.
        - Elman, Mischa
        - Epstein, Henry
        - Ernst, Morris L.
        - Farley, James A.
        - Fidelity and Deposit Co. of Maryland
        - Filene, E. A.
        - Flynn, John T.
        - Freud, Sigmund
        - Gest, Morris
        - Giannini, Amadeo Peter
        - Grant, Jane
        - Green, Belle A.
        - Hammerslaag, Sylvia
        - Hand, Charles A.
        - Harmsworth, Alfred C.
        - Harriman, William A.
        - Hart, Schaffner & Marx
        - Hays, Will
        - Henderson, Leon
        - Hershey, Burnet
        - Heyman, David
        - Hill, George W.
        - Hotel Association of New York
        - Ingersoll, Ralph M.
        - Inter City Radio Communications Service
        - Johns, Orricks
        - Jones, Robert E.
        - Kahn, Otto Hermann
        - Kaltenborn, H. V.
        - Kelly, Grace
        - Kerensky, Alexander
        - Kingsley, Walter J.
        - Klaw, Joseph and Alonzo
        - Kreuger, Ivar
        - LaGuardia, Fiorello
        - Leslie Banks & Co.
        - Little Opera Co. of America
        - Liveright, Horace
        - Lorimer, George H.
        - Lowell, Joan
        - Lucy Stone League
        - Macfadden, Bernarr
        - McGrady, Edward F.
        - Manassas Industrial School for Colored, Manassas, Va.
        - Marsh, Reginald
        - Masaryk, Thomas
        - Merritt-Chapman & Scott
        - Miller, Gilbert
        - Moller, Helen
        - Moskowitz, Belle
        - Murray, Virginia
        - NAACP (Box I:459)
        - New Jersey Telephone Co.
        - Obolensky, Serge
        - O'Keefe, Georgia
        - Paley, William S.
        - Pearson, Drew
        - Phelps, George H.
        - Procter & Gamble Co.
        - Ramsdell, Sayre
        - Reichenback, Harry
        - Roosevelt, Eleanor
        - Ross, Harold
        - Sanborn, Pitts
        - Sanger, Margaret
        - Schicht, George
        - Schulte, David A.
        - Seligmann, Jacques
        - Sell, Henry B.
        - Sokolsky, George
        - Stark, Louis
        - Stern, J. David
        - Stewart, Milton
        - Sullivan, Mark
        - Swope, Herbert Bayard
        - Taft, William H. (1857-1930)
        - Thomas, Lowell
        - United Fruit Co.
        - United States Radium Corp.
        - Vanderlip, Frank A.
        - Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York, N.Y.
        - Wallace, Irving
        - Wasson, Gordon
        - Wildenstein Galleries
        - Wile, Frederick W.
        - Wise, Stephen
        - Worth, Jacques
        - Wylie, Philip
        - Zemurray, Samuel
      - Chronological file (Box I:460)
        - 1890-1919
        - 1919-1925 (Box I:461)
        - 1920-1927 (Box I:462)
        - 1927-1946 (Box I:463)
        - 1947-1961 (Box I:464)
    - Drafts
      - Chapters I-XII
      - Chapters XIII-XVI (Box I:465)
    - Fragments, undated
    - General correspondence (Box I:466)
      - Boorstin, Daniel J.
      - Dodd, Mead & Co.
      - Doubleday & Co.
      - Houghton, Mifflin & Co.
      - McGraw-Hill Co.
      - Miscellaneous
      - Otis, Elizabeth
      - Prentice Hall Co.
      - Simon and Schuster, Inc.
      - Van Auw, Ivan, Jr.
      - Variety
- Part I: Edward L. Bernays' Foundation File, 1946-1963 (Box I:467-471)
  Correspondence, minutes of meetings, legal documents, press releases, and financial papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material, except for financial papers which are filed at the end of the series.
  - General correspondence (Box I:467)
    - 1950-1961
    - 1961-1963 (Box I:468)
  - Minutes of meetings, constitution, and by-laws, 1949-1961
  - Press releases, 1949-1954
  - Subject correspondence (Box I:469)
    - American Sociological Society Award, 1949-1952
    - Barnard College, New York, N.Y., 1950-1951
    - Boston Symphony Esplanade concert, Boston, Mass., 1959
    - College presidents' letters, 1959
    - Hawaiian award, 1951
    - Herald Tribune (New York) article, 1954
    - Juvenile Delinquency Committee, 1955
    - Karelsen & Karelsen, 1946-1961
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology-Harvard University One Day Conference, Cambridge, Mass., 1955
    - National Association of Educational Broadcasters, 1954
    - National Public Relations Association, 1956-1957
    - New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y., 1953-1954 (Box I:470)
    - New York University, New York, N.Y., lectures, 1949-1951
    - One Day Conference on Television Advertising, proposed, 1954-1955
    - Shakespeare in Central Park, New York, N.Y., 1959
    - Social Responsibility of Management, by Stuart Chase, 1951
    - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Sciences, 1948-1952
    - Southern Conference Education Fund, 1946-1948
    - WNYC Institute of Education, 1954
  - Financial papers (Box I:471)
    - Canceled checks, 1946-1952
    - Bank statements, 1946-1952
    - Check stubs, 1946-1960
- Part I: Doris Fleischman Bernays File, 1923-1961 (Box I:472-477)
  Drafts, galley proofs, printed copies of speeches and articles, research notes, correspondence, and a daily appointment book.
  - Careers for Women (1928), correspondence and statistical data, 1927-1928 (Box I:472)
  - "Going Steady" (unpublished), 1946 (Box I:473)
    - Correspondence and research notes
    - Drafts and personal interview notes (Box I:474)
  - "The Last Strike" (unpublished) (Box I:475)
    - Correspondence, galley proofs, and drafts, 1946-1947
  - Speeches, 1939-1961 (Box I:476)
  - General correspondence, 1923-1930
  - Rejected short stories, 1926-1944
  - Subject correspondence (Box I:477)
    - Authors Guild, 1958
    - Luncheon for African-American colleges, 1954
    - New York Committee for Young Audiences, 1961
    - Woman Pays Club, 1958-1961
    - Women's Conference Group, 1959-1960
- Part I: Lists, 1943-1961 (Box I:478-495)
  Index cards and printed lists of names and organizations.
  Arranged chronologically. The majority of the lists consist of index cards arranged by subject within each year.
  - 1943-1946 (Box I:478)
  - 1947-1948 (Box I:479)
  - 1949-1950 (Box I:480)
  - 1949-1956 (Box I:481)
  - 1951 (Box I:482-484)
  - 1951-1952 (Box I:485)
  - 1951-1953 (Box I:486)
  - 1953 (Box I:487)
  - 1954-1955 (Box I:488)
  - 1955-1956 (Box I:489)
  - 1956-1957 (Box I:490)
  - 1957-1961 (Box I:491)
  - 1958-1959 (Box I:492)
  - 1960-1961 (Box I:493)
  - Undated (Box I:494-495)
- Part I: Miscellany, 1896-1963 (Box I:496-509)